for the next method to reduce hit time
let's revisit the relationship between
the associativity and hit time so if we
have high associativity in the cache we
will have fewer conflicts for the set in
the cache when multiple blocks want to
use the same set which leads to a lower
miss rate and that we like with high
associativity we have just seen we can
build larger virtual index physical
little caches which reduces the miss
rate and so we like that too but high
associativity leads to slower hits the
hit time goes up and that we don't like
on the other hand if we go all the way
to direct mapped cache it's the Miss
rate goes up for these two reasons and
that is bad but the hit time is reduced
because the direct mapped cache has only
one place where a block can be so we can
quickly check whether it's there or not
and we like that so we can see that high
associativity in a cache improves the
miss rate but makes the hit time worse
while simple direct mapped cache is
sacrifice the meets rate to improve hit
time so now we will see if we can get
this and this simultaneously by kind of
cheating on our associativity